Chebesi EdyLionel Awah

Full Stack Developer (MERN)

Douala Cameroon chebesiawah@gmail.com +237 6 77 97 21 26

I am a Self taught freelance developer who learned how to build high performance web and mobile apps by watching videos on Udemy and YouTube since 2019. Over the past years, I have ameliorated my skills while working on diverse projects from clients across different parts of the world.

I am specialized in projects using MERN stack, because I just love MERN.

- · I am a good team worker,
- Attentive to details,
- · Quick to learn,
- And I love challenges

I love sports, particularly football, am interested in world politics, dancing and taking walks.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Sponsorship required to work in the US

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Sponsorship required to work in the US

Work Experience

Front End Developer

Icemix.net - Douala January 2022 to July 2022

Worked on the User interface of their project currently in development. We built the frontend using Vue js and Bootstrap

Front End Developer

Virtual Pro Gaming - Mason, OH September 2021 to November 2021

I worked on a project that used React Js and Typescript. Using React Query, I had to interact with the server, getting data from the back and displaying it on the client side. I also updated the User Interface of the client side using libraries like Materia UI.

Front End Web Developer

Silver Line Startup - Douala January 2021 to August 2021

Developed User Interfaces using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and React Js . I also had tasks that involved fetching data from the server using APIs. Aided the team in updating company's website as well as redesigned user experience for websites

Full Stack Developer

BEWOCA NGO - Bamenda January 2020 to December 2020 I built and managed their Web application for the NGO using React, Node and MSQL.

Education

Diploma in Full Stack Web Development

Udemy

January 2019 to December 2019

B.A. in Law and Public Administration

University of Yaounde 2 Soa - Yaounde, CM October 2011 to August 2014

Skills

- HTML5
- MongoDB
- TypeScript
- Bootstrap
- Vue.js
- React Native
- Express.js
- MySQL
- JavaScript
- CSS
- Node.js
- React js
- Firebase
- Material UI
- JSON
- Unit Testing
- Git
- AJAX

Links

https://chebsportfolio.netlify.app

https://www.linkedin.com/in/chebesi-awah-b891331ab

Certifications and Licenses

FreeCodeCamp JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

May 2022 to June 2022

Licenses & certifications freeCodeCamp JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Issued Jun 2022 \cdot

No Expiration Date Credential ID fccd9ff51ad-ee2b-49ac-bdb2-422d3b15a5c2